Fathur Rohman

- hi.fathur.rohman@gmail.com
- +62 896 9951 8803
- linkedin.com/in/fathurrohman
- github.com/fathur

Experienced almost 10 years in developing web application & RESTful API for company or startup. Most likely use Laravel and Rails, but also experienced using Django and React. Very excited to explore cloud service such as AWS and GCP. Delivered best performance REST API using best practices, and also implemented the best technology for the company.

Educations

University of Indonesia

Master of Information and Technology | -

Paramadina University

Bachelor of Information and Technology | 2008 - 2012

Certifications

Oracle Certified Associate, MySQL 5

Oracle | Nov 2013 - not expired

OC1307215

MTCNA

MikroTik | Aug 2013 - Jun 2014

1308NA010

Skills



Experiences

Senior Backend Engineer Full Time

Julo

Nov 2021 - present | Jakarta, Indonesia

Engineer the authentication and underwriting mechanism using **Python**. Also monitoring the performance using **DataDog** and improve it.

Fullstack Developer Contract

Continuum

Apr 2021 - Sept 2021 | United States

Develop web application as a frontend and backend using **React** and **Typescript** and host it inside **Vercel**. We also utilize AWS services, such as **DynamoDB** end **Cognito**.

Sehati-TeleCTG

Lead Backend Engineer Full Time

Jan 2019 - Apr 2021 | Jakarta, Indonesia

Lead a small team of backend to perform achievement in each sprint.

Backend Developer Full Time

Apr 2018 - Dec 2018 | Jakarta, Indonesia

Create a RESTFul API using Ruby **Padrino** framework, powered by Rails ActiveRecord as ORM.

Software Engineer Full Time

Ciavo

Jun 2015 - Mar 2018 | Jakarta, Indonesia

Designing architecture in AWS and developing backend RESTFul API using PHP **Laravel**. We utilize **Oracle 11g** and **MongoDB** as database.

Full Stack Web Developer Contract

Fostrom

Mar 2014 - Jun 2015 | Jakarta, Indonesia

Since this is a digital agency, I help to make various web applications for clients using **Wordpress** and customize or create own themes.

Staff Datacenter, Application, and Database Contract ID-SIRTII/CC

Jan 2012 - Feb 2014 | Jakarta, Indonesia

Organization below Indonesia government to handle digital security incident. I help to handle bare metal server in datacenter, creating application support using PHP **Codelgniter** (IDS).